hotelnewsnow.com 2019-12-30

# HNN

Privacy and Security  
Effective as of 25 May 2018

**Who We Are**

Hotel News Now (“HNN”) is a division of STR, LLC, and, along with STR’s affiliate STR Global, Ltd, and STR Sector Analysis, LLC, is part of the STR Group.

HNN and the STR Group are privacy conscious organizations. This means we are committed to protecting the privacy of all individuals who interact with us, whether by registering as a subscriber to website or submitting information to us. This approach to privacy applies to all personal information received by us from our visitors and subscribers, whether in electronic, paper or verbal form. It also applies to how we use that information and the choices that are available to you regarding our use of your personal information. 

**Privacy Shield**

The STR Group, through STR, LLC, and STR Sector Analysis, LLC, has applied to participate in and has certified to the U.S. Department of Commerce, which has jurisdiction over us, that it will operate with the Department in compliance with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework (the “Privacy Shield). STR Group has stated to the DOC that it is committed to ensuring that all personal information that is received or transferred to us from the member countries of the European Union and the European Economic Area is and will continue to be handled according to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this Privacy Policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>.

If you have any questions or complaints about our compliance with the Privacy Shield, please contact us at [legal@str.com](mailto:legal@str.com) or send a letter to our U.S. headquarters at STR, LLC, 735 East Main Street, Hendersonville, Tennessee, USA 37075, Attention: Legal).

If we cannot resolve your complaint, or if you do not receive a timely acknowledgement of your complaint from us, you may submit the complaint at no-cost to the American Arbitration Association (AAA®) and its international division, the International Centre for Dispute Resolution (ICDR®) at <http://go.adr.org/privacyshield.html>.

Under certain limited circumstances, if all other remedies have been exhausted to no avail, European Union individuals may invoke binding Privacy Shield arbitration as a last resort.  Please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction> for information on when you may invoke binding arbitration.   To initiate binding arbitration, you must give notification of this decision to STR at legal@str.com or send a letter to our U.S. headquarters STR, LLC, 735 East Main Street, Hendersonville, Tennessee, USA 37075, Attention: Legal).

General information about the Privacy Shield and the Privacy Shield Principles, as well as information about binding Privacy Shield arbitration, can be found at [www.privacyshield.gov](http://www.privacyshield.gov/).

**Please note that STR,  LLC, is also subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the United States Federal Trade Commission.**

**What Information Do We Collect From You and When?  
**  
We collect personal information about you when you register to use our websites, or when someone in your organization asks that you be added as a user; when you enroll on behalf of your company in our benchmarking program; when you request more information on products or services; when you request one of STR’s executives speak to your group, company or association; when you register for, or agree to sponsor or present at our Hotel Data Conference; or when you order reports and other products from us. We will also ask for your personal information if you participate in one of our surveys or other research methods which we conduct on behalf of third-party travel and tourism companies or on our own behalf

For our HNN site, if you are merely visiting the site, but not registering or subscribing to any content, we do not collect any personal information about you. However, we may track your activity on the site using cookies, our content management system and third-party analytics sites (see more information below).

The personal information we may collect typically consists of your name, an email address, phone number and mailing address at which you wish to receive communications from us, and may include your credit card and/or banking information if you are using a personal card or account. If you are participating as a speaker in our Hotel Data Conference, in addition to the foregoing, a photograph, your curricula vitae/biography and audio/visual recordings of you may be used. 

If your business or you as an individual consumer are a participant in one of our surveys or other research projects, in addition to the above information, we may ask for sensitive information such as, but not limited to, your gender preference, age, occupation, household income, post code/ZIO code, residency, or other personal information to achieve our research objectives.

Also, to ensure that our websites are well managed and to facilitate improved navigation within the sites, we or our service provider(s) use cookies (small text files stored in a user’s browser), web beacons (electronic images that allow the websites to count visitors who have accessed a particular page and to access certain cookies), or similar tracking technologies (collectively, “Tracking Technologies”) to collect aggregate data. Specifically, we use such Tracking Technologies to track information on our systems and identify categories of visitors by items such as IP address, domain, browser type and pages visited. These Tracking Technologies do not collect any additional personal information about you. We do not link the information collected by these Tracking Technologies to your IP address or anything that could be considered personally identifiable information. 

The tracking technologies include Google Analytics for tracking on all of our websites, and Clicky and StatCounter for our Hotel News Now website. Visitors to our Tourism Consumer Insights division’s website ([www.ljresearch.co.uk](http://www.privacyshield.gov/)) will encounter a “pop-up” application provided by Tawk.to which gives those visitors the option to engage with us in real time. 

You may learn more about how Google uses the information it collects by visiting the following site: “How Google uses data when you use our partners' sites or apps” (located at [www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/)). Google’s ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to our websites is restricted by the Google Privacy Policy (located at [www.google.com/policies/privacy/](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/)). Similar information about Clicky may be found at [https://clicky.com](https://clicky.com/terms) and <https://clicky.com/terms>. StatCounter privacy and use information are found at [https://statcounter.com](https://statcounter.com/). Tawk.to functionalities and other information may be found at <https://www.tawk.to/>. 

Finally, we may obtain personal information about you from other sources, such as from others at your place of business (if our main contact at your company asks us to add your name and email to a list of individuals who may be granted website access or be added to a company distribution list), organizations to which you belong or are a member (usually where we are conducting surveys on behalf the organization), and public websites (to confirm office address and contact information). To the extent we combine information obtained from these sources with other information we may have collected about you, we will treat the combined information as personal information under this Privacy Policy. Of course, we are not responsible for the accuracy of any information provided to us by a third party. 

**Do Not Track Policy  
**  
“Do Not Track” is a proposed standard that is currently under development. As it is not yet finalized, we adhere to the standards set out in this Privacy Policy and **we do not currently respond to “Do Not Track” signals on our websites** **.**

 **How Do We Use The Information That We Collect from You?**

Your personal information is used by the STR Group for various business reasons, all of which are intended to provide you with reliable, timely and excellent data service and analytics, including:

• To register you as a user on our websites and other client portals. This applies whether you signed up directly with us as a user, or were identified as a user by someone within your organization.   
• For invoicing purposes and for credit card payment processing, using a third party vendor.   
• To contact you (whether by phone or email), if necessary, about your order.   
• If you are an employee or representative of one of our hotel clients, to contact you to inquire about your data or your competitive set selection, and to discuss your contract renewal.   
• To notify you about other STR Group products and services, or any STR Group events, in which you may be interested.  
• To notify you about any updates or maintenance to our websites.  
• To notify you about any corrections or delays in our data reporting.   
• For marketing and advertising purposes, if we have received your consent to send you these communications. However, we do not sell our client lists to any other third parties for use in their marketing campaigns. Also, at any time you may opt out of receiving such marketing materials and solicitations from us.  
• In relation to our Hotel Data Conference (HDC), for the purpose of registering you as an attendee and sending you updates prior to and during the conference. In addition, we will provide HDC sponsors with the list of attendees free of charge and as a benefit to them. If you are an HDC attendee but wish to limit how your contact information is used you may opt out.   
• STR Group webmasters use cookie information to analyze the number of visitors to different areas of the websites, to determine how long users are remaining on the sites, and to make sure that our websites are serving as a useful, effective information source for you.   
• To contact you to inquire whether you wish to participate in a consumer survey on behalf of third party travel and tourism organizations.   
• If you are a main point of contact for a hotel company, for inclusion in the STR Directory (formerly the AH&LA Directory).   
• To analyze and report on the results of surveys or other research methods.   
• To comply with our legal and contractual obligations, to resolve disputes and to enforce agreements.

You may object to our use of your information for any of these purposes and you may ask that we case such use at any time by contacting us at [privacy@str.com](mailto:email:privacy@str.com) or calling our U.S. headquarters at 1-615-824-8664 extension 3340. **Please note that if we fulfill a particular request we may no longer be able to communicate with you or provide you with news, information, data or other services you or your company has been receiving from us** **.** ****

**With Whom Do We Share Your Personal Information? How Long Do We Keep it?**

Your personal information may be shared between and among STR, LLC, in the United States and STR Global, Ltd, in the UK, with offices in Germany, Beijing, Dubai, Australia, Brazil, Singapore, and Spain, for purposes of enabling HNN and the rest of the STR Group to provide you with current hotel industry news, as well as the optimal data and analytic services that our customers expect. 

We also contract with third party data processors to help us store, catalog and process your contact and payment/credit card information for our sales, service and marketing activities. Among these third parties are SalesForce (cloud based Customer Relations Management), Cvent (Hotel Data Conference registration), MailChimp (marketing and promotional emails), Azure (online data storage), and Proofpoint (email firewall). We require all third party data processors to keep confidential the personal information that we disclose to them and to only use such personal information for the purpose for which it was disclosed. Please let us know if you would like more information about how we work with these companies. We recognize that, under certain data privacy laws and regulations, STR Group may be liable for the actions of those agents and processors we use to process your information.

As stated above, if you are an attendee at our Hotel Data Conference, we may share your contact information with certain corporate sponsors of the Conference. 

We may provide information to regulatory authorities and law enforcement officials in accordance with applicable law or when we otherwise believe in good faith that the law requires it. There may be instances when we may access or disclose your information in order to protect or defend the legal rights or property of the STR Group or their employees and agents, to protect the safety and security of users, and to protect against fraud.

The STR Group may sell, transfer or otherwise share some or all of its assets in connection with a merger, reorganization or sale of assets, or in the event of bankruptcy, without your permission. In such an event, personal information may be one of the assets transferred.

We will not share your information with any other party, for any reason, unless otherwise disclosed at the point of collection. If that occurs, you will have the opportunity to refuse to give us consent or to withdraw your consent if previously given. 

We retain your personal information for as long as needed to provide you or your company with our services. We also retain and use this information as necessary to comply with legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce agreements. If you are a participant in a survey, we retain your personal information until we have completed the project for the third party for whom the survey was conducted.

 **You May Access Your Information, Correct It And Delete It.**

We are dedicated to providing reasonable access to visitors who wish to review the personal information we have retained so that they may correct any inaccuracies it may contain or opt to delete the information. 

If you wish to see the information about you that we have in our possession, if you wish to correct this information or if you wish to have it deleted in its entirety from our systems, please email us at [privacy@str.com](mailto:privacy@str.com) or call 615-824-8664 extension 3340. 

While we will respond to your request as quickly as possible, please allow us no more than 30 days for any personal information about you to be accessed, extracted modified and/or deleted from our servers and those of our third-party vendors. 

We will certainly respect and fulfill your request to have your information removed from our system. **However, please note that in certain cases (such as where you are on a distribution list or identified as the contact person for a hotel that is participating with us) such removal may result in you no longer having access to HNN news and information or to STR Group reports and data, being able to take part in ongoing research in which you may have previously indicated you wanted to participate, or hearing about new or updated STR Group products, services and events. Also, if you are the main contact for your company, or are the person identified to receive invoices on behalf of your company, we will first need for you to identify the person who will be your replacement. We will assume that you have the authority to provide us with that person’s contact information.  
**

**Also, please bear in mind that, even if we delete your information, it may still persist on back-up tapes and archival documents or electronic media on which other business critical information is stored and which STR must retain for legal, tax, or regulatory reasons, or for legitimate and lawful business purposes. Access to such archival information is limited to only authorized personnel who are under an obligation to maintain its confidentiality.** ** **

**Other Choices About Your Information**

In addition to the options described above, the following mechanisms are available that allow you to control information that is collected about you and your use of our websites:

**•  Tracking Technologies.** You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of our websites may then be inaccessible or not function properly.

**•  Google Analytics Opt-out Option.** If you do not want your information collected with Google Analytics, you can install the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on. To opt-out of Google Analytics, visit the Google Analytics opt-out page (located at <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>) and install the add-on for your browser. For more details, visit the “Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on” page (located at <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/181881?hl=en>). At this time, similar opt-out features are not available through Clicky, Tawk.to, or StatCounter.

**How Do We Protect Your Information?**

The STR Group takes appropriate administrative, physical, and technical measures (collectively “Security Measures”) to protect your personal information from loss, misuse, unauthorized access or disclosure, alteration and destruction. We follow generally accepted standards when implementing and maintaining such Security Measures, including, but not limited to, TLS/SSL for data in transit, limiting unnecessary access, using encryption, using services such as a 24x7 Security Operations Center (SOC), monitoring for unauthorized access attempts, filtering access attempts and mitigating activities by bad actors. These Security Measures are periodically reviewed and, if necessary, updated to ensure they meet current generally accepted standards. Furthermore, only authorized personnel have access to personally identifiable information. Such employees are required to maintain the confidentiality of this sensitive data. This policy also applies to any and all agents and third party data processors that may receive such information from us. Website visitors who provide personal information to us through our websites should be aware, however, that our websites may contain links to third party sites that are not governed by this Privacy Policy or any other privacy statement.

No method of transmission over the internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee the absolute security of information that is transmitted to us electronically. Any transmission of personal information is at your own risk. We are not responsible for circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures we provide. If you have questions about the security of your personal information, our websites or other systems on which your personal information may be transmitted, please do not hesitate to contact us at privacy@str.com or call us at 1-615-824-8664 extension 3340. 

**Third-Party Websites**

This Privacy Policy does not apply to any third party websites or to other companies or persons that may access our websites, with or without our permission. Our websites may contain links to, and media and other content from, other sites. In addition, such third-party media and content may also contain external links. Because of the dynamic media capabilities of our websites, it may not be clear to you which links are embedded in our websites and which are embedded in third-party media and/or content. The STR Group cannot and does not guarantee the privacy policies and practices of any third party. We do not control, operate, or endorse any information, products, or services of any third-party websites that may be reached through links from our websites. 

The use of any personal information provided by you to, or automatically collected from, a third party will be governed by that party's privacy policy. If you are unsure whether a website is controlled, affiliated, or managed by the STR Group, you should review the privacy policy at each linked website to determine how that site treats your personal information.

 **Protecting Children  
**  
Our websites are not intended for children under 13 years of age. The STR Group does not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. If you are under 13, do not use our websites or provide any information about yourself to us, including your name, postal address, telephone number, email address or any screen name or user name you may use. If we learn we have collected or received personal information from a child under 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information. If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at [privacy@str.com](mailto:privacy@str.com) or call us at 1-615-824-8664 extension 3340.

 **Your California Privacy Rights**

California Civil Code Section § 1798.83 permits users of our websites that are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please contact us at [privacy@str.com](mailto:privacy@str.com) or call us at 1-615-824-8664 extension 3340. Please note, however, that the STR Group does not disclose personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes unless we have previously obtained your consent.

 **Future Changes to Our Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy was last revised in April 2018. The law and technology is always changing, as is how we interact with you. Therefore, the STR Group may need to modify or amend this privacy statement at any time. If so, we will notify you. Any changes to this Privacy Policy will be in effect as of the “Last Updated” date referenced in this Privacy Policy.   
For Complaints or Further Inquiries: If you have any questions about our privacy policy and practices or if you have a complaint about how your data has been handled by the STR Group, please contact us: 

By email: [privacy@str.com](mailto:privacy@str.com)  
By phone: 1-615-824-8664 extension 3340  
By mail:  
 **STR,  LLC**  
 **Attention Legal Department**  
 **735 East Main Street**  
 **Hendersonville, TN, USA 37075.**
